What's up, boys?
What's up, man?
How's it going, man?
How's it going, brother?
How you doing?
This is James.
James, nice to meet you, man.
What's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
My business has done, did $149 million last year,
and we should do double that this year.
About a million and a half dollars.
Most I've ever made in one year is $10 million.
$10 million.
You became a millionaire at 30 years old.
Yeah.
Eventually, you became a billionaire.
What was the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
What's the best financial advice I ever received?
Miami, Florida is one of
the top cities in the world
with the most millionaires.
We're back in Miami asking multimillionaires
how they became successful
and how you can start your path
to becoming wealthy in today's world.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I started out in e-commerce.
Now we're in mergers and acquisitions
and largely in real estate as well.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
So last year was our largest month.
We made about $5 million gross,
about $3.9 million net.
This year, we're on track.
We're already at $6 million.
And so valuation is $10 million gross.
We're hoping to close about $7.9 of that net.
And so we're at $6 now.
So we're already beaten last year.
And that's the beauty of scaling and having a system.
If you can put the right people in place
and delegate your work,
then you're able to grow a business.
A lot of people want to be that solopreneur.
I will do everything myself,
so I don't have to pay anyone.
But if you start to delegate to us,
that's when you're going to start to see major growth.
And that's the reason,
the main reason why we're seeing growth this year
is because I learned how to build a team
and build a system.
Throughout your career as an entrepreneur,
what has been your secret to sales?
How have you been able to consistently sell products
at a high volume over your career?
So sales is psychology.
And one thing that you got to learn
is that if you can make someone believe
that something is, first of all, a limited edition
and that it's exclusive,
you can get them to buy anything.
Did you guys hear about,
there was a video of,
they set up like a fake,
um, luxury store.
It was called like Papelli.
And all they had was pay less shoes in there,
like $20 shoes.
But they named it Papelli,
put a little asterisk on there,
had $800, $900 price tags on these $20 shoes.
And people were coming in,
lining up to pay $800
for some shoes that cost $20.
Branding.
If you can brand your business,
if you can brand yourself,
you can sell anything to anyone at any time.
What's the best financial advice
you would tell the younger generation of kids
coming out of school today?
100%, man.
I would tell them,
first of all,
everything that glitzes isn't gold.
Everyone that you see driving a Lamborghini
and wearing flashy clothes,
they aren't actually rich.
The thing about social media
and the world these days
is that everyone is selling a lifestyle
that a lot of people aren't living.
And then you go broke
trying to keep up with that lifestyle.
Don't keep up with the Joneses,
even if you are making money.
I know more millionaires
who have sat back,
lived below their means
and built their funds over time
than I know millionaires
who made a million dollars in one year
and then started buying Lamborghinis
and luxury clothes.
The best financial advice I could do
is live below your means
invest, invest, invest,
accumulate your money,
compound interest,
open a Roth IRA,
invest in your Roth IRA
every single year,
compound all of your money,
no matter what you do,
compound your money
and you will be rich.
I don't care how long it takes,
you will be rich.
This is 100 years.
Poor people think in weeks and months.
Rich people think in years,
in decades.
That's how you get rich,
by thinking long term.
Stop thinking like that
get rich quick stuff
is going to get you broke real quick.
That's amazing, bro.
You killed that shit, bro.
All right, you guys,
we are now in Sunny Isles.
This is a different community
in Miami.
It's a very high class area,
but we're here to interview
a nine figure solar company CEO.
We're going to ask him
how he was able to scale his business
from not just seven to eight,
but eight to nine figures
and really get some game
for all the young and hungry
entrepreneurs out there.
Let's get it.
Yo, what's up guys?
How are you, man?
Good, man.
Nice to meet you, man.
Nice to meet you.
Zane, nice to meet you, man.
What industry did you decide
to pursue a career in?
So I went all into solar energy.
Why?
Because I believe that
that was the most important thing
that I could do at that time.
I went selling door to door,
got very good at the product,
learned the customer base,
learned the proposal.
And then I got into
installing the stuff,
actually learning about the technology,
how it's built,
building a team of construction workers,
engineers, designers.
And that led to me building
one of the largest solar companies
in the United States today.
Elon Musk once said,
you get paid in direct proportion
to the size of the problems
that you solve.
And so you're the CEO
of one of the largest solar companies
in the entire country.
So what has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
My business has done,
did 149 million last year,
and we should do double that this year.
So you're on track to do
about 300 million this year?
Correct, yeah.
So let me ask you,
what was the biggest thing
that you've implemented in your business
to take it from not only seven to eight,
but eventually eight to nine figures?
To get to seven figures,
you need a really good idea
and really good sales and marketing.
To get to eight figures,
you need a really good team.
If you have the right people around you,
you'll be able to get to eight figures.
But to get to nine figures
is one of the hardest things to do.
You not only need a really good product,
you need really great marketing,
you need really great sales,
you need a really great team.
But most,
most importantly,
you need systems.
You need SOPs,
standard operating procedures.
In my company,
there's a standard operating procedure
for everything we do.
And this is a little bit of a joke
and exaggerated,
but there's legitimately
a standard operating procedure
if you want to go to the bathroom
or if you want to make coffee.
The whole point of that
is for every system
and function in the business,
it has to be documented.
Because if it is documented,
that means that if I get sick today,
I can pass my colleague that document
and they can actually do my work function.
So therefore,
you are no longer relying on me.
And when you are an eight-figure business owner,
a lot of times,
people are still relying on the CEO.
But when you become a nine-figure business owner,
people aren't just relying on the CEO anymore.
They're relying on the machine and the system.
So the CEO could die,
but the machine and the system will continue to scale.
So to me,
that's where most people get stuck
at that eight-figure range.
So you've got hundreds of millions of dollars
coming into the company that you're dealing with.
Correct.
But what's been the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
If there's one lesson that a mentor,
or somebody taught you about money,
that's always stuck for you,
what is that advice?
Spend your money.
Everyone is gonna be like,
what?
Everyone says save your money.
Save your money.
Pour it in the bank account.
No, the only way that you can build something
is by pouring into it.
It's like,
imagine if you had a brand new Bugatti parked downstairs,
but there was no gas tank to put fuel in.
So you literally couldn't drive it.
That's exactly what a bank account's like.
You have a $5 million bank account
that's not working for you.
It's literally like a Bugatti with no gasoline.
It's like an art piece.
Like you're just gonna look at it,
and it's gonna deteriorate in value every single year.
When you have money in your bank account,
do not look at it as something to protect you.
Look at it as something to make you more money
and make you more successful.
I get so anxious when
we look at our bank account
and there's so much money in there.
Why?
Because I'm like, what are we doing with this?
We don't need this right now.
We have all of our expenses, our operating costs,
everything is taken care of, payroll is made.
Let's put this money to work.
So those are my fundamentals and principles with money.
I will never, ever hoard my money.
I will always put it back.
I will always put it back into something.
All right, you guys,
that was an absolutely incredible experience
to go out and film with Zane.
He's got a nine figure company.
He's gonna make $300 million with his business this year.
But we got another surprise for you.
We are back in Brickell, Miami,
about to go interview an eight figure agency owner,
Robert Miller.
He's from Austin.
We've met him before,
but he invited us out to his crib in Miami
to really give us some game
on how he was able to
scale from seven to eight figures.
Let's go see what he has to say.
What's going on, boss man?
Hey, hey, what's up guys?
Good to see you, man.
Good to see you.
Awesome.
The last time we connected with you,
obviously we were in Austin, Texas.
Yeah.
But now we're out in Miami, Florida.
Why the transition?
Why go from Austin to a city like Miami?
Well, first off, I mean,
this is one of the reasons right here.
Austin has great views, great real estate,
but there's nothing like Miami
in regards to what you can actually get.
Number two is the entrepreneurship crowd out here.
Way more people that are here doing big things.
And so I believe in investing into your environment.
So it first starts with the home,
first starts with your casa.
Then is the people that you surround yourself around.
And then lastly, man, I mean the beach.
I had to have a beach, man.
The beach is right here.
That's amazing.
And you've got an incredible spot here in Miami.
Can you show us around a little bit?
Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely.
Here is the first balcony.
I have two balconies here at the spot.
And so being able to look out at the water,
it's very inspiring.
Obviously you get to see how busy the city is,
but right over here is the financial district.
And so it's really great to go network
and communicate and connect with people that are out there
because they're in finance and I love finance.
And so that's typically one
of the things that I do.
That's typically one of the places to go hang out
and go do your thing.
So for those that don't know,
what industry did you pursue a career in?
Like how many businesses do you own right now?
Yeah, so I have a couple of different businesses.
Right now it's five.
I first got exposed to digital currencies
when I was about 17,
18 years old, so prominently Bitcoin.
And then from there,
I went straight into digital marketing and e-commerce.
And so throughout the portfolio of businesses
that I have right now,
it's really a cash generation machine
to then invest into digital currencies,
whether it's that Bitcoin, Ethereum,
or other coins that we may choose.
But mainly it's been digital marketing,
e-commerce and crypto.
And how much money would you say
your businesses are gonna do this year?
This year, we'll probably do over 15.
Next year, we're projected to do about 20 to 25.
But assets under management,
our target is about 50 million
by the end of the year.
That's incredible.
And for someone who has a business
and maybe they're able to
hit that one $2 million mark,
they can hit seven figures consistently,
but they don't know how to get to eight.
What's the biggest thing you changed about your business
that took you to eight figures?
You know what's funny?
I actually went and saw Grant Cardona
and I asked him that exact same question.
I know you guys just interviewed him.
And the one thing that he told me,
and it seems pretty simple,
but the one thing that he
said was just follow the graph.
And you're like, okay, what does that really mean?
Well, you have your revenue graph,
which is obviously how your sales and marketing
are actually performing.
The second is with social media marketing,
as you guys know, follow the impressions,
follow the content,
follow where the algorithm is taking you
and continue to double down in those areas.
Because sometimes we psych ourselves out
by not looking at data.
And usually the entrepreneur that hits the first million,
or maybe the second million,
they lack the data infrastructure
because you can hustle your way
to the first or second seven figures.
And once you have data to
be able to help you make decisions,
then you start to see that parabolic growth
because you're making the right decisions
and the right improvements
on the things that are actually needed.
What would you say has been the best financial advice
that you've ever received throughout your career?
The best advice I got was connecting yourself to revenue.
And so some people, they go into the sales job,
but it actually first starts with marketing.
And so if you can control the lead flow,
then everyone's gonna want you
because you are bringing money
to those businesses.
So it gives you a unique opportunity
if you understand marketing and then sales,
because if you don't have anyone to talk to,
then you can be the best salesman in the world,
but it doesn't matter, you have no leads.
So if you learn those two skill sets,
any business will be able to want you
because that's what they need
and that's typically what they struggle with.
All right, you guys, we
just finished up at Robert's spot.
And man, he was super nice to have us out
to his new Miami pad.
It's got an insane spot out here in downtown Brickell.
But I wanna ask you,
what would you say is the biggest lesson
that you get from being surrounded
by these young eight and nine figure entrepreneurs
like Zane, like Robert?
What has being surrounded by them
really done for your mindset
and just your view on money and everything in general?
You know, being surrounded by young guys like Zane, Robert,
it really shows you that their vision
is so much greater than where they are right now.
They could be eight or nine figures right now,
but that's not all that they want.
They wanna shoot for the top of the mountain.
What they're doing right now
is nothing compared to where they wanna go.
It's just a reminder that even when you accomplish
really great things and you achieve a certain level
that might be greater than what most people are doing,
just remember at the end of the day,
the only person you're competing with is yourself.
And so just being surrounded
by them being a part
of that energy is just like,
damn, I just gotta keep smashing
through every fucking ceiling
and every fucking wall that's in front of me
until I hit the top of the mountain.
Absolutely.
And I have one more
thing to add on to that.
Like and subscribe to the School of Hard Knocks
for some amazing content and stay tuned
because the biggest surprise yet of the channel
is coming at the end.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I started in online training.
I was one of the
people that, I didn't invent it,
but I was one of the pioneers
of online training back in 08, yeah.
What's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Most I've ever made in one year,
if you count everything,
you count investments and my businesses,
most I've ever made in one year is 10.
10 million.
What's the greatest lesson
that you've learned about entrepreneurship
that you would pass on to someone
who's starting a business in 2023?
The greatest lesson is, you know,
the more you sweat during peace,
the less you bleed during war.
When the C-19 and all the other stuff happened
and some people were panicking, laying people off, weak.
I didn't lay off nobody.
In fact, I started hiring people, right?
Cause I had prepared for those situations.
And when I was doing really well,
I made sure that I stacked money, I stacked bread,
and I just had a whole bunch of savings.
I told all my employees
that we're not laying nobody off.
Even if we don't need you, just chill.
And one of my mentors told me that the reason
most businesses can't last 10 years
is because there was a recession every 10 years, right?
Everybody looks like a genius when times are going good.
Only the real Gs can handle it through the recessions.
So what is the secret to being recession proof?
And even though during those times,
regardless of what's happening in the economy,
what's the secret to surviving that?
Well, you know, in my opinion,
I think it's one, just having a bunch of money
or access to money,
cause that could be credits
or if you don't want to keep cash,
or it can be assets
that you can take loans against
if things going right.
Cause you want to just
be able to have, be liquid.
When the shit really hits the fan,
it doesn't affect you and or you can capitalize on,
you know, when everything goes on sale.
Another thing is skills, right?
I know no matter what, if everything hit the fan,
I know how to market and sell well enough
that I can just call one
of my friends who has a business
and be like, yo, let
me sell for you or something.
Worst case scenario, or, you know,
let me run your ads or something.
And I can make some money pretty relatively quickly.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate you, bro.
Man, Miami is an absolute movie.
I can't believe we just ran into Brandon Carter.
That's King Keto.
He's one of the OG fitness influencers
that really pioneered that niche.
Made over $10 million in a single year
and dropped some great game
for the young and hundred entrepreneurs out there.
Miami's crazy, man.
Let's go get this next one.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I'm in the healthcare industry.
I'm a cardiovascular and thoracic surgeon.
What inspired you to kind of pursue
medicine, pursue the healthcare industry?
Well, in my case, it was my mother's death.
I was about 10 years old
and I watched her bleed to death after childbirth
and there was no doctor to save her life.
So I decided I wanted to be a doctor.
So no child would have to experience what I'd experienced
watching her suffer.
And no parent would have to suffer like she did.
And for someone who may be on their last year
of medical school this year, what would you tell them?
What's the blueprint that it takes
to become a successful surgeon in this industry?
What it takes is a passion for human service,
first of all, and a sacrificial mentality.
That you have to stay so focused
because medicine is huge.
There's a lot to learn.
It's a very long career,
but you can't have any other interferences.
You gotta stay really targeted and very focused
and strive to be the best doctor you can be.
In doing that, you wanna be the best
at everything that you do.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
About a million and a half dollars.
A million and a half, sir.
For someone who's aspiring to
go from six to seven figures
in their career, what would you tell them?
What does it take to kind of,
mindset shift, like what did you implement
that allowed you to get from six to seven figures
in your career?
A love and passion for what you do
and a strive for excellence.
Be so good that nobody
can do it better than you.
And then the money comes.
If your priority is the money,
more than likely you'll fail.
If it's excellence, the money will come with it.
Thank you so much for your time, sir.
I really appreciate that.
No problem.
Have a great day.
Good luck to you.
Man, Miami's been absolutely insane,
but I want you to comment down below
who's been your favorite interview and why.
We wanna connect with you guys
and know all what you guys think about this video.
All right, you guys,
we got a very special surprise
for you.
We are here at Cardone Enterprises
to interview Grant Cardone.
Grant Cardone was one of the entry entrepreneurs
who I started to watch.
That really got me serious
about wanting to become financially free
and starting businesses.
The three of us are so excited
to deliver this content and get this interview.
Can't wait to see how it goes.
How's it going, man?
How's it going, brother?
How you doing?
James.
Good to meet you, man.
You became a millionaire at 30 years old.
Yeah.
Eventually, you became a billionaire.
Mm-hmm.
What was the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
Well, I don't know if it's a piece of advice
I received about money.
Look, money's just a tool, man.
And I was brought up by,
my mother, she didn't understand money,
so she taught me to manage it.
I learned just doing undercover billionaire, okay?
It wasn't what somebody taught me.
I was put in a situation where
I was given $100, and they said,
you need to use this $100 to build a business.
And I looked at it and I'm
like, okay, how do I do this?
I'm like, well, $100 is not
a way to build a business.
So to go from 100 to 10,
I wanted to build a
$10 million business in 90 days
without using my name.
They dropped me off in Pueblo, Colorado.
So I'm looking at it like a puzzle.
I need to go from 100 to 10 million.
And I'm like, what's the
fastest way to get to zeros?
Because when you're going from 100 to 10 million,
what are you trying to add?
Zeros, that's all you're trying to add.
And I'm like, oh, the fastest way to go there
is to go straight to zero.
Just take the 100 and get rid of it.
So rather than trying to add to it, right?
Rather than trying to add to it, I'm like,
oh no, just go to zero.
Got rid of the $100.
I told Discovery, here, take the 100 bucks back.
And they're like, we don't want the 100 bucks back.
I said, take it back, I
don't want it, I don't need it.
So I basically just go to
zero as fast as I can.
And then I stay at zero the whole time, okay?
And I'm like, okay, I
need people, I don't need money.
Because the tendency is to manage your money.
So the lesson I learned was quit managing money, okay?
Managers don't make money.
Do you know of a wealthy manager?
No.
Fund manager, Goldman Sachs,
they're not managing money.
What are they doing?
They raise money and then they invest it.
And they raise money and they invest it.
That's how they make their money.
So like, go to zero, man.
Don't have any money.
Do not save money.
Don't plan for retirement.
Take every penny you earn from every person you meet
and reinvest that money.
Reinvest it in something that it's your business,
your marketing, your brand, your information,
getting better, faster, more confident.
Anything that makes you faster, better.
And then when something's left over,
start investing in other real assets.
Invest in, what do you guys live?
Austin?
Yeah, start buying real estate.
Next 18 months is gonna be the greatest
real estate opportunity in your lifetime.
Maybe for the next 50 years.
Thank you guys so much for watching this video.
Miami was an absolute movie.
Be sure to leave a like and subscribe
for amazing content coming soon.
And click here to watch our full interview
with real estate billionaire, Grant Cardone.